<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Shane Steinert-Threlkeld&#39;s blog</title>
  <subtitle>Posts from Shane Steinert-Threlkeld, with no promised frequency or content, though usually covering book reviews, trip reports, and miscellaneous academic thoughts.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://shane.st/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://shane.st/" />
  <updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://shane.st/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Shane Steinert-Threlkeld</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>_Thirty Below_ by Cassidy Randall</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/thirty-below/" />
    <updated>2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/thirty-below/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9781419771538&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thirty Below: The Harrowing and Heroic Story of the First All-Women’s Ascent of Denali&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Cassidy Randall (audio).  In some ways, the subtitle tells it all: this book recounts teh first all-women’s ascent of Denali, which was also the first such ascent of any of the highest peaks in the world.  As Randall puts it early in the book: we had put a man on the moon before a woman on a high peak.  I first heard about this book during a tour through the climbing podcast world&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;For instance, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/episode/76AIVjndCoESTvfjNbCWX8?si=x1NmsDycRim_PUOjN1KpMA&quot;&gt;this episode&lt;/a&gt; of the American Alpine Club’s podcast.&lt;/span&gt; and was excited to see that my local library already had it available as an audiobook.  The book goes into great detail about the obstacles facing women in climbing and mountaineering at the time—shocking to hear in the concrete even if known in the abstract—and tells a riveting story of the climb itself, pieced together from everyone’s journals and the few written accounts&lt;label for=&quot;sn-1&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-1&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Some memoir chapters, an American Alpine Journal article, and some local newspaper articles, but no national media coverage.&lt;/span&gt; previously available.  Anyone who loves reading alpine memoirs will enjoy the book for that dimension.  But what really sets this book apart is how well Randall builds the characters involved.  We learn about the leader Grace’s two failed attempts to climb Denali which, on top of the sexism she experienced, created a drive and stubbornness to get to the top that bordered on (probabl crossed over) reckless or dangerous.  Other characters are equally or more complex, and the resulting dynamics—taking place in the thin air above 18,000 feet—add richness to the story that makes it hard to put down.&lt;label for=&quot;sn-2&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-2&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;One meta-comment: podcasts are great, but this book is a great example of the limits of that medium.  The clif-notes version that I heard on a podcast was interesting enough, but contained almost none of the rich texture and character development that made this book what it is.  It’s good to have a concrete reminder in the value of long-form writing and paying attention thereto.&lt;/span&gt;  Grade: A&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_The Lost Trees of Willow Avenue_ by Mike Tidwell</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/lost-trees-willow-ave/" />
    <updated>2025-04-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/lost-trees-willow-ave/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9781250362261&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lost Trees of Willow Avenue&lt;/em&gt;, Mike Tidwell&lt;/a&gt; (audio). This book tells the story of the impact of climate change and what might be done about it through a very interesting literary lens: it tells the story of a group of large oak trees on the author’s street over teh course of one year.&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Whence the subtitle: &amp;quot;A Story of Climate and Hope on One American Street.&lt;/span&gt;  In contrast to large-scale statistics about the overall climate around the globe, this hyper-local story-telling helps make vivid that the impacts of global warming are already literally on our doorstep.  The book has several main characters. First, there are the large oak trees, which are victimized by a crippling heat dome in 2023 and resulting bettle infestations (not to mention dramatic flash flooding events), the loss of which both not only saddens locals but also greatly changes local ecosytems.  Secondly, there’s Ning Zheng, Tidwell’s neighbor and scientist, who is pioneering the idea of burying dying trees as a method of carbon capture.  Ning also serves as skeptical backdrop to one of Tidwell’s main personal aims in the book: to assess the feasibility (and possible necessity) of solar geoengineering, i.e. using things like aerosols to reflect some sunlight away from the earth’s surface as a method of cooling.  Thirdly, there’s Jamie Raskin, Tidwell’s representative in the US House, with a riveting story both in politics and his personal life.  These are primary characters, against a backdrop of many other personal stories told throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story-telling is neatly divided into chapters based on month.  So we get the story of one street through one year, with many other characters coming and going.  Tidwell’s a great writer, who can be forgiven for the occasional literary flourish.&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;For example, at the end of one chapter, with a very grandiose ending, I fully expected to hear “This concludes the presentation…”.  But perhaps this also has to do with the audio medium.&lt;/span&gt;  The book tries to provide hope—not least because Tidwell himself is looking for hope—but does not shy away from the realism of what is happening all around us.  Zheng, for instance, does not provide the simple assurance that Tidwell hopes he might.  Another source of hope: perhaps humanizing the problem in the way this book does will make more people willing to advocate for what must happen to save our planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grade: A-&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_Beyond the Mountain_ by Steve House</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/beyond-the-mountain/" />
    <updated>2025-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/beyond-the-mountain/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9780980122770&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beyond the Mountain&lt;/em&gt;, Steve House&lt;/a&gt;. I picked this book up used for $4 at the public library in Bozeman, Montana awhile back and finally got around to reading it recently.  House is someone who I know a decent amount about, but mainly from reputation and from training resources&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;For instance, I’ve read &lt;a href=&quot;https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/training-for-the-new-alpinism/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Training for the New Alpinism&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; since his days at the bleeding edge of alpine climbing predate my interest in climbing.  This memoir recounts his career from 1990 through 2005, beginning as a rather green member of a Slovenian expedition to Nanga Parbat and culminating in his alpine-style ascent with Vince Anderson of the Rupal face of the same mountain.&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;For which they won the 2006 Piolet D’Or, becoming the first North Americans to do so.&lt;/span&gt;  Along the way, we meet a person singularly dedicated to climbing as much as possible, often at the expense of other aspects of life like romantic relationships.  A long-term relationship, for instance, ends roughly because he doesn’t feel the depth of connection with his partner that he did with his climbing partners on a speedy ascent of the Slovak Direct route on Denali.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book ends with depictions of House’s reluctance to be in the spotlight after his climbs: an unexpected welcome ceremony in a local village after the Nanga Parbat, the Piolet D’Or awards ceremony, and a talk at the Ouray ice festival.  When reading the book, one often feels the same hesitance.  The prose is extremely direct.  While this has some refreshing qualities—House only occasionally enters into tired cliches about the mountains—it leaves the reader wanting more sometimes.  The book does have its literary moments. The description of the Rupal face climb jumps back and forth between the climb and the descent, creating a dizziness in the reader at first that must be a (very dim of course) reflection of their mental state.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like House, the book thrives in the climbing sections, with very detailed accounts of what it really takes to get up and down some truly awe-inspiring lines in the big mountains.  Just like House, the book leaves the reader wanting more emotional depth, feeling like there’s more behind the surface that we don’t get to see.  In that sense, this memoir might indeed be a true reflection of its author.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My Corner of the Web</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/my-corner-web/" />
    <updated>2025-03-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/my-corner-web/</id>
    <content type="html"></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_Amusing Ourselves to Death_ by Neal Postman</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/amusing-ourselves-to-death/" />
    <updated>2025-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/amusing-ourselves-to-death/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9780143036531&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amusing Ourselves to Death&lt;/em&gt;, Neal Postman&lt;/a&gt; (audio).  I learned of this book from the great &lt;a href=&quot;https://drlennecefer.com/&quot;&gt;Len Necefer&lt;/a&gt;, most recently in his post-election post &lt;a href=&quot;https://drlennecefer.substack.com/p/the-algorithm-wont-save-us&quot;&gt;The Algorithm Won’t Save Us&lt;/a&gt; and his subsequent departure from Meta platforms.  Reading this book—written in 1985 on the heels of Reagan becoming president—in February 2025—on the heels of Trump’s second term—felt eerie.  Postman’s central claim is that “the medium is the metaphor”: the structure of the dominant media in which public discourse takes place shapes how the public conceives of truth and justification.&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;Whence the subtitle “Public discourse in the age of show business”.&lt;/span&gt;  He argues that the transition from a print-based mode of discourse to a television-baesd mode of discourse has fundamentally changed the nature of public discourse, from one in which long, reasoned arguments were entertained by the public&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;As evidenced, for instance, by the extremely long form of debates in 17- and 1800s America.&lt;/span&gt; to one in which short, context-free nuggest of &lt;em&gt;entertainment&lt;/em&gt; are the dominant currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the book has its idiosyncracies—I found his discussion of photography to be somewhat vapid, and he spent an unusually long time discussing television evangelists—the history of information transmission, including the crucial distance-erasing effect of the telegraph, and the core argument are both compelling and have held up forty years later.&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;At separate times, he claimed that TV’s aesthetic preferences meant that no overweight person would become president, and that TV favors conciliatory messaging, so no red-faced angry person would become president. These claims have proven to be very obviously and sadly false.&lt;/span&gt;  Once concept that felt particularly apt to our current time is “The Peek-a-Boo World” (the title of Chapter 5).  Postman accuses television of trading in very small units that are de-contextualized and disconnected, in a way resembling a game of peek-a-boo.  His least favorite words appear to be “Now, this”, due to the abrupt transition between small units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accusing TV of creating a Peek-a-Boo world feels comical when algorithmic feeds like TikToks have reduced so many people into passive consumers of long streams of very short-form video content.  We all know the dopamine rush these feeds cause and euqally well the feeling of emptiness after scrolling for too long.  Doom-scrolling no longer refers to scrolling for purely negative news, but rather for the sense of doom one feels after losing track of how long one has been hooked on the feed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our public discourse has transformed even more deeply into an entertainment-based one in the 40 years since Postman’s book.  This depresses greatly but also motivates.  I’ve been working to break free of algorithmic feeds and shorter-form content myself and have been enjoying the restorative effects on my attention span and well-being (more on this in a later context).  Although I’m certainly not alone in this effort, this book does make one wonder: how can we change the dominant media landscape in a way that promotes a healthy, rational public discourse?  I hope that it’s possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
TODO: figure out / debug sidenote.js to get id working for label
--&gt;
&lt;!--
This book is a classic, and for good reason.  Postman&#39;s thesis is that the medium of communication shapes the content of communication, and that the shift from a print-based culture to a television-based culture has had profound effects on public discourse.  Postman&#39;s argument is compelling, and his examples are well-chosen.  The book is a bit dated, and some of the examples are a bit stale, but the core argument is still relevant today.  Postman&#39;s writing is clear and engaging, and he makes his points effectively.  The book is a bit repetitive, but it&#39;s a quick read and well worth the time.  Grade: B+
--&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_Tender is the Flesh_ by Agustina Bazterrica</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/tender-is-the-flesh/" />
    <updated>2025-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/tender-is-the-flesh/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9781982150921&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tender is the Flesh&lt;/em&gt;, Agustina Bazterrica&lt;/a&gt;.  My first novel in a little while, this one was a shop’s pick in Charleston, SC during a visit to my mom for the new year.  It’s disturbing.  The premise: in a near-future world, a global virus has spread among all animals, forcing them to all be killed.  In response, sanctioned and regulated cannibalism has become the norm.&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;Or did it? Several characters allude to a conspiracy theory, that the virus was a hoax so that the government could tighten regulation and control the population.&lt;/span&gt; Some of the regulations are linguistic: euphemisms (“the Transition”, “meat”, “head” to refer to a human bred for meat, etc) serve to mask the reality of what’s going on.  Some are not: the breeding process is very regulated to create humans that in a sense lack humanity (no names, no vocal chords, etc).  The protagonist works high up at a meat-processing plant.  He—his name is Marcos, but he’s almost uniformly referred to as “he” and the like—is a troubled soul: he does not like the work and the resulting dehumanization, but does so to take care of and provide for an ailing father.  He also has dark events in his past that contribute to his dissociative day-to-day existence.  While the book depicts truly gruesome events—detailed descriptions of a tour through a human slaughterhouse, a “game hunting” operation, and the like—the plot moves relatively quickly and the narration of Marcos’ inner-life keeps the reader grounded.  The prose is moving as well. At one point, an entire paragraph spanning two pages uses a long sequence of comma-separated clauses to both describe and mirror the mental chaos of a traumatic event.  I do not want to say too much about the plot,&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;The book has two “parts”, which are separated by a particular event which does, in a sense, change everything.&lt;/span&gt; but will just say: the ending genuinely surprised, and somewhat shook me.  The take home: Marcos—as we all are I suppose—is still just human after all.  Grade: A&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_The Uncanny Muse_ by David Hadju</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/the-uncanny-muse/" />
    <updated>2025-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/the-uncanny-muse/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9780393540833&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Uncanny Muse&lt;/em&gt;, David Hadju&lt;/a&gt; (audio).  This book’s subtitle—“Music, Art, and Machines from Automata to AI”—captures its greatest virtue: it provides both an illuminating and entertaining history of the role of machines in the arts as both of them have evolved throughout history (at least since around the 1600s).  Although it does contain many examples of visual art, including a long episode of Andy Warhol and the wider New York art world around the founding of MoMA and various exhibits of machines and art (including machines-as-art), it’s also no accident that the subtitle begins with “Music”: Hadju shines as a historian of music, telling of the development of the microphone, the player piano, electric organs, synthesizers, and the (embarassingly unknown-to-me) history of house music.  Hadju’s telling of the history flows smoothly and listens easily; corner-stone objects or moments provide for natural, and often unnoticed, transitions between historical episodes.  Tracing this history shows the cyclical nature of a debate that is re-surfacing now: new technologies are often thought to threaten human creativity, but oftentimes become accepted and expand it.  With that being said, two thoughts on Hadju’s handling of the present, LLM-driven moment, which felt like the weakest section to me.  On the one hand, he admirably does not directly argue for one view or another, but mostly just presents a history.  On the other hand, his use of ChatGPT to write a few paragraphs about its own history&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;This explained the eye-rolling paragraph: “Over time, ChatGPT underwent a series of metamorphoses, each iteration reefining its linguistic dexterity and cognitive acument.  The model, akin to a virtuoso refining their technique, absorbed vast swaths of diverse data, learning to navigate the linguistic tapestry of the internet and replicate the multifaceted richness of human expression.”&lt;/span&gt; and repeated emphasis of “the machine condition” in addition to the human condition lead one to believe that the present moment is just the latest instance in this historical cycle.  As I’m sure many people have, I’ve been having some currently-uncoalesced thoughts about asymmetries between LLM-generation and other machine-assisted art (which I’ve both produced and been a fan of at different times).  This book hasn’t necessarily increased the coalescence of my own thoughts, but has provided rich fodder for them due to the excellent re-telling of some important historical episodes.  Grade: B+&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_States of Adventure_ by Fitz Cahall</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/states-of-adventure/" />
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/states-of-adventure/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9780744092714&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;States of Adventure&lt;/em&gt;, Fitz Cahall&lt;/a&gt;.  This book was a perfect holiday gift for me.  Part coffee-table photo book, part adventure memoir anthology, it contains 30 relatively bit-sized stories distilled from Cahall’s podcast &lt;em&gt;The Dirtbag Diaries&lt;/em&gt;.  That show is the original outdoor/adventure podcast, and one of the earliest podcasts period.  I’m ashamed to say I’ve never listened to it (though I’ve listened to Cahall’s other show &lt;em&gt;Climbing Gold&lt;/em&gt;, and various interviews with him), so I can’t attest to the direct mapping from podcast episode to chapter in this book (though it is clear that they are not transcripts; many are also not written by Cahall, but by others who either lived the adventure or did the primary reporting).  For the most part, the stories were great reading and viewing.  Some were downright moving: a team of strangers banding together to carry a taken-too-soon-by-disease man’s boots through the Appalachian Trail so that they at least could fulfill his dream.  (This one felt like an antidote to the isolation that has created some of the larger problems in our world right now.). Some felt like they didn’t translate well into written form.  While I’m sure the story of the youngest rafting descent through the Colorado River in the Grand Canyon was riveting, the written word was not: “The river pulled her in.  Each wave formed its own deep canyon.  The kayaks acclerated down the backside of the wave.”  While certainly not nearly AI slop, some writing like this had a certain average-of-all-adventure-writing genericity reminiscent of ChatGPT’s “style”.  Some were especially enjoyable because they hit close to home: Fitz Cahall is a fellow Seattleite, almost exactly 10 years my senior, so I especially enjoyed hearing about his transition into family life with a trailer in Crystal Mountain’s famous Lot B, skiing down the iconic Brothers in the Olympic mountains, and his evolution as a climber in and through Index.  The book certainly has something for everyone, and I will happily pass it around and tell folks about many of the stories, though with a tongue not quite as silver as Cahall’s.  Grade: A-&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism_ by Amanda Montell</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/cultish/" />
    <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/cultish/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9780062993151&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cultish: The Language of Fanaticism&lt;/em&gt;, Amanda Montell&lt;/a&gt; (audio).  I stumbled upon this book just through browsing the Libby app, but thoroughly enjoyed it.  The name comes not just from analyzing cult-like groups, but is intended to evoke English and Spanish, in highlighting how language is used to form and shape groupthink.  Terms that were new to me—but labeling phenomena which are very much noticeable—include “thought-terminating cliché”  (aka “semantic stopsign”) and “love-bombing”.  Although it did include detailed analyses of several typical cults (e.g. Scientology, Jonestown, Heaven’s Gate), I especially appreciated the discussion of group fitness trends like CrossFit, SoulCycle, and Bikram yoga.  When I first became serious about physical training (for ultimate, in college), CrossFit was nearing its peak influence; luckily, I was able to extract some useful information while smeleling something a bit fishy in its celebration of suffering and zealousness of its supporters. (I also did a non-trivial number of Bikram classes during grad school.)  The final section covered social media influencers, highlighting a few from the wellness space that were news to me. The book also has a nice pace, with a clear structure, which also lent itself very well to the audio format.  Grade: B+&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>_On Writing_ by Stephen King</title>
    <link href="https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/on-writing/" />
    <updated>2025-01-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://shane.st/blog/book-reviews/on-writing/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/a/111171/9781982159375&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;On Writing&lt;/em&gt;, Stephen King&lt;/a&gt;.  This is (ironically?) the first thing I’ve read by Stephen King.&lt;label for=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle sidenote-number&quot;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; id=&quot;sn-0&quot; class=&quot;margin-toggle&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sidenote&quot;&gt;test a sidenote.  If it gets too long, then what happens?&lt;/span&gt;  I’ve owned it for many years, buying it during one of those pangs of doubt near the end of grad school; maybe this would be the book that turned the pangs into a new self-conception.  Needless to say, I’m not sure what prompted me to finally pick up after so long; even after I got tenure.  Oh: probably the book I’m over 18 months late on and the grant application I had to delay as well.  Anyways: great read.  I see why Stephen King has had the success that he has.  The book opened with a memoir section; a rather turbulent and fragmented childhood was mirrored both in the prose (short, punchy sentences) and in the structure (very short numbered sections) in a very satisfying way.  I won’t go too much into the details of either his life or his suggestions (I think the four hours a day, every day, line has been repeated enough; and a small few things were a bit too specific to fiction writing), but will mention one other thing that stood out to me: his approach to writing as a craft (of course it is!), and the analogies to other crafts like plumbing.  I remember during grad school reading the introduction to Michael Dummett’s &lt;em&gt;A Logical Basis of Metaphysics&lt;/em&gt;, as erudite and obscure a book as exists (look at that title!), and being struck by the line, “Philosophy, after all, is a craft, as plumbing is”.  Several similar moments met me in King’s book.&lt;span class=&quot;marginnote&quot;&gt;How about a margin note? And what if I make it really really long?&lt;/span&gt;  Great read.  Not the last of his for me.  Grade:  A-&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>